So now let's talk about fine-tuning on Amazon bedrock.
So fine-tuning is going to be a big part of your exam.
So the idea is that you're going to adapt a copy of a foundation model,
and you're going to add your own data.
So when you fine-tuning a model,
it's actually going to change the underlying weights of the base foundation model.
So you need to provide training data and it needs to adhere to a specific format,
and it needs to be stored into Amazon S3.
So the idea is that, for example, you have the LAMA2 model,
and you're going to add data from Amazon S3,
such as this data or that data and we'll have a look at this data very specifically in the next slides.
And then bedrock is going to do it something,
and you're going to get a fine-tuned version of LAMA2,
which has your own data as well.
So in order to use a fine-tuned custom model,
you must use what's called provision throughput,
which is a different pricing model than on-demand.
And note that not all models can be fine-tuned,
but you can end the usually open source.
So how can we fine-tuning a model?
Well, we have instruction-based fine-tuning.
And here, this is to improve the performance on the pre-trained foundation model,
on domain-specific tasks.
So what does it mean domain-specific tasks is that you'll see an exam?
That means it's going to be further trained on a particular field or area of knowledge.
And here, the trick you need to go and look for the exam
is that instruction-based fine-tuning is going to use what's called labeled examples,
and they're going to be prompt responses pairs.
So it's for labeled data,
and the prompt response pairs look at this,
the prompt is who is the fanarek, for example,
and the completion, so the response is,
stiff fanarek is an able-to-structure who dedicates his time
to make the best AWS courses,
so that his students can pass all certifications with flying colors.
So here, on top of giving information to the model,
we are also throwing the model how he wants it to order some questions,
such as who is the fanarek.
Maybe the answer the model had would be already similar,
but with a different tone.
So this is where instruction-based fine-tuning is helpful.
Next, we have continued pre-training.
So here, the idea is that we continue the training of the foundation model.
So here, because we know foundation model
I've been tried using unlabeled data, we need to provide as well
for continued pre-training unlabeled data.
And so this is something you look for in the exam,
if you have unlabeled data, this is a kind of fine-tuning you need.
And so it's also called domain adaptation fine-tuning
to make a model an expert in a specific domain.
For example, I'm going to feed the entire AWS documentation
to a model, and then the model is going to be an expert on AWS.
So here, we're just giving all documentation
with its unlabeled data, so this is continued pre-training.
And now, the model has become a domain expert.
So here's the kind of input you have here.
As you see, there's no prompt output, there's just inputs.
And the input is just a lot of information.
So here, this information is around financial data.
And as you can see, if you want to read through it,
it has a lot of acronyms.
And so this is very good to teach acronyms
or feed industry-specific terminology into a model.
And then you can keep on training the model,
it's called continued pre-training, as more data becomes available.
OK, next, you may encounter as well single-turn messaging
and multi-turn messaging.
So this is a subset of instruction-based fine-tuning.
But the idea is that here, we're going to give a hint
into a user and an assistant.
What the user is asking and what the assistant,
so the bot should be replying.
So here we have system.
This is optional context for the conversation.
Messages, which is going to contain various messages.
Each will have a role, which is the user of the assistant,
and the content, which is the text content of the message.
So here we're fine-tuning how a chatbot should be replying.
And for multi-turn messaging, this is the same idea,
but this time we have a conversation.
So we have multiple turns.
And so here we alternate between user and assistant roles.
And we have a conversation and this helps the model understand
how to handle conversations with bigger contexts.
So good to know for fine-tuning.
First of all, retraining and financial model
requires a higher budget because you need to spend
some computations on it.
So instruction-based fine-tuning is usually going to be cheaper
because the computations are less intense.
And usually, you have less data required.
You're just trying to fine-tune how the model
is replying based on specific instructions.
If you use continued pre-training, it's usually more expensive
because you need to have a lot more data.
Also, it requires you to have an experienced machine-learning
engineer to perform the task, even though the drug
makes it easy for you.
And you must prepare the data, you must do the fine-tuning,
and also evaluate the model.
And finally, because you have a fine-tuned model,
it's also more expensive because you have to use provision throughput.
So now let's talk about transfer learning.
So transfer learning is a bit broader than fine-tuning.
It is the concept of using a pre-trained model
to adapt it to a new related task.
For example, we have Cloud 3, and then we're
going to do transfer learning to adapt it to a new task.
So you say maybe it's very similar to fine-tuning,
and it is.
But for example, for image classification,
we may want to use a pre-trained model
that knows how to recognize edges and images.
But we may want to do transfer learning
to apply it to recognize specifically a kind of image.
Or for language processing type of models, for example,
birth or GPT.
Again, they know how to process the language.
So now that we have the language figured out,
let's just find to them or use transfer learning
to adapt it to newer tasks.
So transfer learning is in this lecture,
because it can appear in the exam as a general machine
learning concept that will be used, for example,
to, as the definition says, adapt a model to a new task.
So if you don't see fine-tuning,
just know that the general answer is to use transfer learning,
because fine-tuning is a specific kind of transfer learning.
So the use cases of fine-tuning is,
for example, to have a chatbot designed
with a particular person, our tone,
or get towards a specific purpose,
such as assisting customer, or crafting advertisements.
It's also to have trained at more up-to-date
than what the model previously accessed.
Also, is to train it with exclusive data that you have only.
For example, historical emails or messages,
or records for customer service interaction.
Of course, base foundation models do not have access to this,
because this is your data.
And for target use cases such as categorization,
or assessing accuracy.
So let's see for fine-tuning.
The exam will ask you about when the fine-tuning
is a good idea, and the kind of fine-tuning you will need
based on the type of data you get, for example,
labeled or unlabeled data,
as well as maybe some pricing questions.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.